Milk, it comes from cows, right?
牛奶都是奶牛产的，对吧？
Well, not all the milk you see on supermarket shelves is from an udder.
但事实上，超市货架上的牛奶并非都来自奶牛的乳房。
These days we see many plant-based alternatives to dairy, such as oat, pea and soya milk.
如今我们能看到许多植物基的乳制品替代品，比如燕麦奶、豌豆奶和豆奶。
But why would someone stop drinking their full-fat, semi-skimmed or skimmed cow’s milk and trade it for one of these?
可为什么有人会放弃全脂、半脱脂或脱脂牛奶，转而选择这些替代品呢？
There are many reasons someone might try alternative milks.
人们尝试植物奶的原因有很多。
Some people believe the alternatives are healthier than milk from cows. Those with lactose intolerance or thinking about becoming vegan might start drinking alternative milks. Also, concerns about the impact of dairy farming on the environment could be a factor.
有些人认为植物奶比牛奶更健康；乳糖不耐受的人群，或是打算成为素食主义者的人，可能会开始饮用植物奶；此外，对奶牛养殖业的环境影响的担忧，也是一个可能的因素。
Whatever the reason, there are many alternatives to dairy out there for us to consume.
无论出于何种原因，市面上都有多种多样的乳制品替代品可供选择。
But what are the differences between these other options and regular cow’s milk?
但这些替代品和普通牛奶之间，到底有哪些区别呢？
Soya milk is one common alternative.
豆奶是一种常见的替代品。
According to some sources, such as healthline.com, it contains a similar amount of protein to regular milk.
据健康资讯网站Healthline等来源称，豆奶的蛋白质含量与普通牛奶相近，热量也比部分牛奶更低，很适合正在节食的人群。
It is also lower in calories than some cow’s milk, which could be good for those on a diet, and often comes fortified with things like calcium and various vitamins.
而且市面上的豆奶通常会添加钙和多种维生素来强化营养。
So, all good?
这么看豆奶是不是完美无缺？
Well, soya is a common allergen, and according to foodallergy.org, is one of the nine foods which cause the majority of allergic reactions.
其实不然，大豆是一种常见的过敏原，据美国食品过敏研究与教育组织的数据显示，大豆是引发大多数过敏反应的九种食物之一。
Almond milk is a low-calorie, low-fat drink and is naturally lactose free and has a slight nutty taste.
杏仁奶是一种低热量、低脂肪的饮品，天然不含乳糖，还带有淡淡的坚果香气。
When unsweetened, it also has lower levels of carbohydrates and sugars than some dairy options.
无糖款杏仁奶的碳水化合物和糖分含量，也低于部分乳制品。
However, even when fortified, it doesn’t provide the levels of protein seen in soya or regular milk.
但即便经过营养强化，杏仁奶的蛋白质含量也比不上豆奶和普通牛奶。
Then there’s coconut milk, which is low in calories and may not affect people with nut allergies as much as other options, but is lacking in protein.
再来看看椰奶，它热量较低，对坚果过敏人群的影响也比其他植物奶小，但同样存在蛋白质含量不足的问题。
Whichever plant-based milk you choose, there are positives and negatives.
无论你选择哪一种植物奶，它都各有优缺点。
Dieticians agree the most important thing is getting a healthy balanced diet which won’t trigger any allergies and comes with all the minerals and vitamins you need.
营养师们一致认为，最重要的是保持健康均衡的饮食，这种饮食不会引发过敏，还能提供身体所需的各种矿物质和维生素。
And at the end of the day, it may just come down to which one you think tastes better.
说到底，选择哪一种植物奶，可能还是取决于你觉得哪一种更好喝。